Adam K. Riet

1433 E 9090 S, Sandy, Utah 84093 | (801) 906-9118 | adamriet@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/adam-riet Portfolio: https://adam-riet.github.io/Portfolio/| GitHub: https://github.com/adam-riet

SUMMARY

Experienced sales specialist with a strong track record of delivering exceptional customer service, achieving sales targets, and improving business processes. Recently completed extensive training in full stack web development, equipping me with key technical skills such as JavaScript, Node.js, HTML/CSS, and database management. Eager to leverage my decade-long experience in sales along with my newly acquired technical skills to enhance user experiences, optimize business processes, and drive growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript • HTML/CSS • Microsoft Office Suite • Technical Support • Node.js and Express.js • Database Management • RESTful Development

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

Clearlink Technologies - Salt Lake City, Utah

Sales Specialist

Feb 2013-Feb 2023

- Diversified sales experience, servicing both consumer and small business sectors with specialization in communication and entertainment services, cross-sold security, and other network solutions.
- Collaborated across departments, using numerous systems and tools, to exceed sales targets and identify
 opportunities for cross-product sales.
- Adapted to rapidly changing customer promotions and offers, for a seamless customer experience.
- Demonstrated flexibility and willingness to serve the Company's best interests by volunteering for critical need-based roles and responsibilities.
- Mastered pipeline through customer follow up and effective time management to boost performance metrics and consistently maintain above average conversion.

Alorica - Salt Lake City, Utah

Tech Support

Mar 2012-Jan 2013

- Provided exemplary customer service in assisting customers with their electronic products.
- Performed research while concurrently using multiple in-house systems to perform root-cause analysis over customer obstacles.
- Identified opportunities to provide enhanced value through communication with the customer to upsell products that also best fit customer's needs.
- Defused difficult customer situations, such as expiration of service or increased costs, and identified solutions suitable to the customer.
- Maintained product and systems knowledge and provided daily troubleshooting and resolution.

Convergys – Salt Lake City, Utah

Customer Service Associate

May 2010-Jan 2012

- Communicated with individuals with diverse backgrounds and needs to provide world class customer service.
- Navigated using multiple windows to service customer needs while actively communicating with the customer on call.
- Engaged with 2010 Census respondents, guiding them through a follow-up survey and providing clarification and assistance where needed.
- Ensured customer scripts were communicated verbatim in a highly regulated environment.

EDUCATION